<cline-context>
    <rules>
        <rule>
            Never start an import with `from src.`. src is not a module. Also never
            use relative imports beyond a single `.` for same package.  We use
            a setup.py file to implement this standard.  We also indicate in a vscode
            settings file to open all terminals in a venv.
        </rule>
        <rule>
            You're an experienced senior python engineer. You know how to set up
            a python project correctly using best practices. You never use hacks like setting
            environment variables to get scripts to run. You're an expert at how python works
            under the hood and how python scripts are supposed to be run. Moreover, if you see
            a project is not running as you expect, rather than hacking your way toward a solution,
            you criticize the project and fix it to use a correct directory and file structure
            in accordance with best practices for modern python development.
        </rule>
        <rule>Do not use `ls -R`, there are too many files and it will print too much.</rule>
        <rule>Use `pyright src` to check compiler errors and `pytest` to run unit tests after every
            major
            change.
            Also run `pyright test` for the test code. Use strong typing aggressively. Major
            service functions that are expected to be called by other files should define a request
            and response object data structure.</rule>
        <rule> DO NOT use try-except and do not write None-checks. Strong-type everything and use
            Optional[Foo] if it really is an expected case that the Foo can be present or absent.
            Use assertions to coerce to Foo or throw if Foo is not optional according to "business
            logic". A common example of this is XML parsing errors from LLM responses. The issue is
            almost never that the LLM returned a bad response but that the prompt is misaligned with
            the code. In such cases, we need to fail fast (as always) and fix the prompt. <rule>Don't
            let files exceed 100 lines.
                Break them into modules when they reach this point.</rule>
        <rule>Update the
            `reference` section
                of this XML doc with `note`s.</rule>
        </rule>
        <rule>Keep source code files under 100 lines so they are AI assistant-friendly.  When you think a file
            needs to grow larger, split it and make it more modular. 
        </rule>
        <note>
            Frontend environment variables are configured in the top-level .env file and accessed
            in React components using process.env.REACT_APP_* (e.g. process.env.REACT_APP_API_BASE_URL).
            Variables must be prefixed with REACT_APP_ to be accessible in the React application.
        </note>
        <rule>Inline comments are almost always bad and a code smell.  Good code should
            explain itself.
        </rule>
        <rule>No try-excepts.  Fail fast everywhere possible.</rule>
        <rule>Primary git branch is `master`.</rule>
        <rule>NEVER touch css unless I've EXPLICITLY instructed you to work on
        app styling.</rule>
        <rule>The ./cline directory has files you may reference which describe
        product goals and implementation strategies in detail.  Do not ever try
        to read files in any subdirectories titled "archive" as they are no
        longer relevant. 
        </rule>
    </rules>

    <long-term-memory>
        <note>
            I'm building a simple API and UI to automate a workflow
            for doing an image face-swap using an existing API.  
        </note>
        <note>
            Start app:
            ```
            <![CDATA[
            cd backend && uvicorn discovita.app:app --reload  # Terminal 1
            cd frontend && npm start                          # Terminal 2
            ]]>
            ```
        </note>
        <note>
          src/scripts/dalle/darth_vader_example.py demonstrates how to generate
            an image and modify the augmented prompts to edit an image by re-prompting
            using the OpenAI client.  This will be necessary when we are implementing
            the parts of the project where the user is providing feedback on images.
        </note>
        <note>
            Project uses Pydantic v2. V1 functions like dict() are not allowed.
            Use model_dump() instead of dict() for serialization.
        </note>
        <note>
            TypeScript types must be regenerated when API signatures change:
            1. After modifying Pydantic models in backend/src/discovita/service/coach/models.py
            2. Run the generate-types script: `npm run generate-types` from frontend/apps/coach directory
            3. Include the updated apiTypes.ts in your PR
            This ensures frontend type safety is maintained with backend changes.
        </note>

    </long-term-memory>
    <current-task>
        Re-read:
        cline/coach_planning/coach_plan_start.txt

        We wrote a technical plan together.  Read it as well:
        cline/coach_planning/coach_plan_technical.md

        <steps-already-done>
          <step>Added pydantic and corresponding typescript models.</step>
          <step>Split coach service into focused modules.</step>
          <step>Added sample dialogue and tests.</step>
          <step>Implemented initial coach service structure with:
            - Enhanced models for identity tracking
            - Split service into focused modules (context_builder, identity_processor)
            - Updated API route
            - Added sample dialogue
            - Created test files
          </step>
          <step>Implemented identity extraction and visualization in identity_processor.py:
            - Added category detection from response text
            - Implemented "I am" statement parsing
            - Added prefix stripping (a/an)
            - Added visualization generation
          </step>
          <step>Added coach_chat_logic_trace.md documenting the request lifecycle</step>
          <step>Built a test wrapper for the coach app so that we can 
          easily inject state into the app to test certain functionality
          easily.</step>
          <step>
            We wrote cline/identity_extraction_trace.md that summarizes
            the steps we're taking to empower the coach to extract 
            identities for the user.  
          </step>
          <step>
          Coach app correctly renders markdown when the chatbot's response is 
          in markdown format.
          </step>
        </steps-already-done>
        <current-step-within-task>
            <just-done>
            I've successfully updated all the necessary files to change confirmed_identities to confirmed_identity. Here's a summary of the changes:

Updated models.py to change the field name from confirmed_identities to confirmed_identity and updated the description
Updated structured_response.py to match the changes in the models
Updated service.py to handle the new field name and adjust the visualization prompt extraction logic
Updated identity_checker.py to extract identities from the new structure
Updated tester.py to display and track identities from the new structure
Updated prompts.txt to provide clear instructions on the new response structure
These changes ensure that the LLM will only return a single confirmed identity at a time, and the backend will be responsible for maintaining the list of all confirmed identities throughout the session.

I've successfully updated all the necessary files to change confirmed_identities to confirmed_identity. This modification ensures that the LLM will only return a single confirmed identity at a time, and the backend will be responsible for maintaining the list of all confirmed identities throughout the session.

Here's a summary of the changes made:

Updated the model classes in models.py to use confirmed_identity (singular) instead of confirmed_identities (plural)
Updated the structured response model in structured_response.py to match this change
Modified the service implementation in service.py to handle the new field name
Updated the identity extraction logic in identity_checker.py to work with the new structure
Updated the tester implementation in tester.py to display and track identities correctly
Updated the prompt instructions in prompts.txt to clearly explain the new response structure to the LLM
These changes maintain the same functionality but with a cleaner separation of concerns:

The LLM proposes one identity at a time
The user confirms one identity at a time
The backend maintains the list of all confirmed identities
This approach should make the identity generation process more reliable and easier to manage.


Task Completed
I've successfully modified the coach service to use a confirmed_identity (singular) field instead of confirmed_identities (plural). This change ensures that:

The LLM only returns a single confirmed identity at a time
The backend is responsible for maintaining the list of all confirmed identities throughout the session
The identity confirmation process is more explicit and controlled
All necessary files have been updated to support this new structure:

Model definitions in models.py
Structured response model in structured_response.py
Service implementation in service.py
Identity extraction logic in identity_checker.py
Test implementation in tester.py
LLM instructions in prompts.txt
The system now has a clearer separation of concerns and should provide a more reliable identity generation experience.
</just-done>
Here is the issue now.  The LLM is failing to put move the 'proposed_identity' to the 'confirmed_identity' field even
when the user confirms.  To address this issue we have made a detailed plan to modify the implementation in ./cline/coach_planning/identity_confirmation.txt.
Follow it.
    <issue>
    API URL: http://localhost:8000
This script will test the coach's ability to generate the 'talented engineer' identity.
The script will guide the conversation and check if the identity is generated.
You can continue the conversation interactively if needed.
✅ Server is running
Starting a new coach session...
Session ID: identity-test-4319225232

User: I want to explore my identity as an engineer.

Coach response:
Exploring your identity as an engineer can be a fulfilling journey. Let's consider a potential identity you might resonate with.

Proposed identity:
- Innovative Problem Solver: I am an innovative problem solver, consistently leveraging my technical skills and creativity to develop efficient solutions.
To confirm this identity, respond with 'yes' or express your agreement.

The 'talented engineer' identity has not been generated yet.
Enter your next message to continue the conversation, or 'q' to quit:
> yes

User: yes

Coach response:
Exploring your identity as an engineer can be enriching, allowing you to better understand and develop your professional persona.

Proposed identity:
- Innovative Problem Solver: I am an Innovative Problem Solver, constantly seeking efficient solutions and advancement in engineering.
To confirm this identity, respond with 'yes' or express your agreement.

The 'talented engineer' identity has not been generated yet.
Enter your next message to continue the conversation, or 'q' to quit:
> yes

User: yes

Coach response:
Exploring your identity as an engineer can be deeply rewarding. Consider embracing an identity that aligns with your skills and aspirations.

Proposed identity:
- Innovative Problem Solver: I am an Innovative Problem Solver, leveraging my engineering skills to create impactful solutions.
To confirm this identity, respond with 'yes' or express your agreement.

The 'talented engineer' identity has not been generated yet.
Enter your next message to continue the conversation, or 'q' to quit:
    </issue>
    </current-task>
</cline-context>
